It's good to have friends that we can talk to and share our thoughts and opinions with.
有能倾诉、能分享想法和观点的朋友是件好事。
More importantly, they're people we can ask for help or advice.
更重要的是，他们是我们可以求助或征求建议的人。
But recently it seems, many of us are developing a new relationship with a mystery person that we'll never meet!
但最近似乎很多人正在和一个从未谋面的神秘人建立新的关系！
I'm talking about virtual assistants or bots.
我说的是虚拟助手或聊天机器人。
These are pieces of software that we can talk to and it can talk back to us.
它们是能与我们对话且能回应我们的软件。
Examples include Apple’s Siri, Google’s Assistant, Amazon’s Alexa and Microsoft’s Cortana.
比如苹果的Siri、谷歌助手、亚马逊的Alexa和微软的Cortana。
It might be on your phone or computer or even a smart speaker in your home.
它们可能在你的手机、电脑上，甚至是家里的智能音箱中。
They are changing the way we interact with technology - instead of typing on a computer keyboard or tapping on a tablet, we can now speak and a voice will answer.
它们正在改变我们与科技互动的方式——不再需要在电脑键盘上打字或在平板上点击，现在我们可以直接说话，就会有声音回应。
The people behind these voices are called conversation designers.
这些声音背后的创作者被称为对话设计师。
Tom Hewitson is one of them.
汤姆·休伊特森就是其中之一。
He told the BBC "this is kind of changing [computers] into like an agent.
他告诉英国广播公司：“这有点像把（电脑）变成了一个代理人。
They’re an active participant in the interaction and in guiding you to make the right decision."
它们是互动中的积极参与者，会引导你做出正确的决定。”
So he's saying this cutting-edge technology has the ability to think for itself and make its own decisions.
所以他的意思是，这项尖端技术有能力自主思考并做出自己的决定。
It is a scary thought that this virtual voice can think for you – will it stop us using our own brains and will we lose the ability to write things down or type?
想到这个虚拟声音能替你思考，确实有些令人担忧——它会让我们不再动脑子，让我们失去写字或打字的能力吗？
They are certainly clever, helping you to book train tickets, give you the latest weather news or even tell you a joke.
它们确实很聪明，能帮你订火车票、提供最新天气资讯，甚至给你讲笑话。
But are they really your new best friend?
但它们真的能成为你的新朋友吗？
One thing we can't do yet is to make chit-chat or small talk with it.
目前我们还做不到的一件事是和它们闲聊。
We have to alter the way we speak.
我们必须改变说话方式。
As Tom Hewitson says "We will develop our own kind of vernacular for speaking with machines that will be subtly different from how we speak to other people…
正如汤姆·休伊特森所说：“我们会形成一种专门与机器交流的用语，这种用语与我们和他人交流的方式会有细微差别……
It can be much more brusque and to the point."
会更加直接、开门见山。”
But there's no doubt this technology will soon be commonplace in our lives.
但毫无疑问，这项技术很快就会在我们的生活中普及。
This year Google Duplex was revealed, described by the company as artificial intelligence "for accomplishing real-world tasks over the phone".
今年谷歌发布了Duplex，该公司将其描述为“能通过电话完成现实世界任务”的人工智能。
It's a type of chatbot that will allow you to, for example, chat to your hairdresser about when they can fit you in for a cut.
这是一种聊天机器人，比如它能帮你和理发师沟通预约理发时间。
Other companies are working on similar things.
其他公司也在研发类似的产品。
But before they perfect this new technology, don't forget who your real friends are!
但在这项新技术完善之前，别忘了谁才是你真正的朋友！